{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Sixth Sense","incorrectAnswers":["The Others","The Ring","The Grudge"],"question":"In which 1999 film does Bruce Willis meet a boy who can see dead people?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Louis XVI","incorrectAnswers":["Louis XIV","Charles IX","Charles XII"],"question":"Which King Was Overthrown As A Result Of The French Revolution?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Elton John","Freddie Mercury","Jim Morrison"],"question":"Which musician wrote the lyrics 'Am I sitting in a tin can? Far above the world, planet Earth is blue and there's nothing I can do'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the studio album 'Jazz'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer released the studio album '…Baby One More Time'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","Bangladesh","Nepal"],"question":"Where is the Taj Mahal?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dire Straits","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","The Moody Blues","The Shadows"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Money for Nothing'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Marlowe","Ben Jonson","John Donne"],"question":"Who wrote the famous play 'Hamlet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Etna","incorrectAnswers":["Vesuvius","Amiata","Pico"],"question":"What volcano showers ash on Sicily? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Richard I","incorrectAnswers":["Henry II","Edward I","Henry VIII"],"question":"Which English king was known as 'The Lionheart'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bite","incorrectAnswers":["Urinate","Bark","Mate"],"question":"A skunk will not __________ and throw its scent at the same time.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"USA","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","England","Australia"],"question":"In which country would you find the Grand Canyon National Park?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brave New World","incorrectAnswers":["Big Old Planet","Strange New Land","Cruel Old Country"],"question":"Which novel, published in 1932, was a vision of the future as a sanitised society?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wild Cherry","incorrectAnswers":["The Cardigans","Sinead O'Connor","Billy Ray Cyrus"],"question":"'Play That Funky Music' was a one hit wonder in 1976 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Scottish","incorrectAnswers":["English","Irish","Welsh"],"question":"Which nationality was the author of the 1817 novel \"Rob Roy\", just like the hero of the story?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Englund","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Lorre","Andy Serkis","Jack Nicholson"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Freddy Krueger in A Nightmare on Elm Street?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lisbon","incorrectAnswers":["Santo Domingo","Suva","Oslo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Portugal?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Chicken","Horse","Pig"],"question":"Yorkshireman William Strickland is believed to have brought the first _______ to Britain from North America in 1526?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cairo","incorrectAnswers":["Venice","Paris","New York"],"question":"Complete the title of this 1985 Woody Allen movie: 'The Purple Rose of ___'.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1966","incorrectAnswers":["1960","1972","1978"],"question":"In which year was The Good, the Bad and the Ugly first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blind Melon","incorrectAnswers":["Debby Boone","Meredith Brooks","Nick Gilder"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1993 with No Rain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Katajjaq","incorrectAnswers":["Hula","Yodelling","Crooning"],"question":"What is the name of the traditional throat singing of the Inuit people of the Arctic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Forrest Gump","incorrectAnswers":["Four Weddings and a Funeral","Pulp Fiction","Quiz Show"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1994?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Uganda","incorrectAnswers":["Bolivia","Mozambique","Nigeria"],"question":"Swahili is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Two grifters team up to pull off the ultimate con.","incorrectAnswers":["A secretary checks into a remote motel run by a young man under the domination of his mother.","An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant.","A weatherman finds himself trapped in a small town as he lives the same day over and over again."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Sting?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Alfred Nobel","incorrectAnswers":["Nikola Tesla","Thomas Edison","Leonardo da Vinci"],"question":"Who invented dynamite?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A ","incorrectAnswers":["B","C","D"],"question":"Carrots Are Rich In which Vitamin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Playboy","incorrectAnswers":["Lamborghini","Peugeot","Nestlé"],"question":"Which of these brands has a rabbit on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Singapore","incorrectAnswers":["Taiwan","Thailand","Myanmar"],"question":"Sir Stamford Raffles founded which Asian nation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Charleston","incorrectAnswers":["Greenville","Greensboro","Wilmington"],"question":"What is the capital of West Virginia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Hamlet","Othello","Romeo & Juliette"],"question":"Which Shakespeare play opens with the 3 Witches?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bread ","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Fish","Mushroom"],"question":"What type of food is a bloomer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Alps","incorrectAnswers":["The Pyrenees","The Urals","The Himalayas"],"question":"What is the name of the European mountain range whose glaciers formed lakes like Como and Constance?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Tycho Brahe","incorrectAnswers":["Johanes Kepler","Galileo Galilei","Nicolas Copernicus"],"question":"Which astronomer had a metal nose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"\"There's Nothing Like A Dame\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Some Enchanted Evening\"","\"Bali Ha'i\"","\"I'm Gonna Wash That Man Right Outa My Hair\""],"question":"Which song from the musical 'South Pacific' begins with the lyrics 'We got sunlight on the sand, we got moonlight on the sea'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Trinidad and Tobago is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Casablanca","incorrectAnswers":["Casa del Sol","Casamor","Casa del Albus"],"question":"What seaport's name is Spanish for 'white house'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'Boy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Five","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Yellow","Black"],"question":"What does the word 'fünf' mean in German?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Poirot Investigates'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Leo Tolstoy","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'War and Peace'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Paraguay","Bahamas"],"question":"In which country is the city of Valparaíso?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Minnesota","incorrectAnswers":["Maine","Washington","North Dakota"],"question":"Which of the 48 contiguous states extends farthest North?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Aioli","incorrectAnswers":["Hollandaise","Béarnaise","Tartar"],"question":"Which sauce is an emulsion of garlic and olive oil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Jose Sharks","incorrectAnswers":["San Jose United","San Jose Bills","San Jose Flames"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in San Jose?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jet Li","incorrectAnswers":["Jackie Chan","Deng Chao","Stephen Fry"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor and Mulan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Searchers ","incorrectAnswers":["The Lookers","The Finders","The Seekers"],"question":"Who had a number 1 record in 1963 with Sweets For My Sweet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ivory","incorrectAnswers":["Diamonds","Gold","Silver"],"question":"For what valuable material do some people hunt walruses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gloria Swanson","incorrectAnswers":["Bette Davis","Barbara Stanwyck","Whoopi Goldberg"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Norma Desmond in Sunset Boulevard?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jack and Jill","incorrectAnswers":["Hey Diddle Diddle","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Girls and Boys Come Out To Play"],"question":"What nursery rhyme is about a couple who climbed a hill?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Magnetron","incorrectAnswers":["Resistor","Diode","Transistor"],"question":"What kind of electronic tube is used to produce microwaves?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lion","incorrectAnswers":["Bat","Peacock","Bird"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the MGM logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Clash of Kings'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nahuatl","incorrectAnswers":["Maya glyphs","Olmec","Isthmian"],"question":"What is the name of the Aztec writing system?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Queen Victoria","incorrectAnswers":["James VI","Elizabeth I","George II"],"question":"Who was the first English monarch to have a Christmas tree?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Edward III","incorrectAnswers":["Richard III","John","Henry III"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1327-1377?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Rubicon River","incorrectAnswers":["The Alps","The City Walls","The Pelegrin Fields"],"question":"What did Julius Caesar cross to signal a revolt against the senate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Billy Bob Thornton","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Seth Rogen","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Fargo and Love Actually?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Little Water ","incorrectAnswers":["Strong Water","Life Water","Fun Water"],"question":"What Does Vodka Actually Mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lobster","incorrectAnswers":["Sea Snake","Dolphin","Jellyfish"],"question":"The crayfish isn't a fish at all _ it is related to the __________","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Vancouver Canucks","incorrectAnswers":["Vancouver Rockets","Vancouver Sounders","Vancouver Lightning"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Vancouver?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rectangular","incorrectAnswers":["Circular","Triangular","Hexagonal"],"question":"The pupil of an octopus's eye is __________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hook","incorrectAnswers":["Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade","Jurassic Park","Schindler's List"],"question":"Which 1991 Steven Spielberg film included 350 pirate outfits for the extras alone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"I Ran (So Far Away)","incorrectAnswers":["I Jumped (So Far Away)","I Hid (So Far Away)","I Long (So Far Away)"],"question":"Which of these was a hit song by A Flock of Seagulls?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Unchained Melody","incorrectAnswers":["Careless Whisper","Let's Get It On","The Lady In Red"],"question":"Which Song Ends With The Line \"God Speed Your Love To Me\"? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tight Fit","incorrectAnswers":["Men at Work","Rick Astley","Cher"],"question":"Who Sang The Song \"The Lion Sleeps Tonight\" In The 80's?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Mongolia","Philippines"],"question":"Which of these countries borders North Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Grace Kelly","incorrectAnswers":["Marylin Monroe","Hedy Lamarr","Rita Hayworth"],"question":"Who was Cary Grant's female lead in the movie 'To catch a thief?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Abraham Lincoln","Thomas Jefferson","George Washington"],"question":"Who was the second President of the USA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["Six","One","None"],"question":"How many stomach compartments does a cow have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Millennium Falcon","incorrectAnswers":["Razor Crest","Ebon Hawk","X-Wing"],"question":"In Star Wars, what is the name of Han Solo's ship?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Finland","Denmark"],"question":"What country's government resigned due to Gustav V's 1914 borggardstalet or 'courtyard speech'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pearl Jam","incorrectAnswers":["Anti-Flag","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which band includes 'Eddie Vedder'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"South Pole","incorrectAnswers":["The Peak of Mount Everest","The Moon","The Mariana Trench"],"question":"In 1911 Roald Amundsen became the first person to reach where?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Sow","A Doe","A Pen"],"question":"What would you call a female elephant?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Leo Tolstoy","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Henryk Sienkiewicz","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Death of Ivan Ilyich'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","England","Ukraine"],"question":"In which country is maotai a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Portugal","The USA","Australia"],"question":"Which country administers Martinique?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the studio album 'The Fame'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nikita Khrushchev ","incorrectAnswers":["Boris Yeltsin","Vlademir Putin","Joseph Stalin"],"question":"Who gave John F. Kennedy a dog named Pushinka? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Pakistan","Nepal","China"],"question":"The Taj Mahal is located in which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Cherries","incorrectAnswers":["The Potters","The Hornets","The Sky Blues"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team AFC Bournemouth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Keep your friends close, but your enemies closer.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"A martini. Shaken, not stirred.\"","\"Soylent Green is people!\"","\"I'm walking here! I'm walking here!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Godfather Part II'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Missouri River","incorrectAnswers":["Mississippi River","Ohio River","Rio Grande"],"question":"What is the longest river in the United States?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kinshasa","incorrectAnswers":["Tunis","Durban","Luanda"],"question":"Which of these cities is in The Democratic Republic of the Congo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Isaac Newton","Galileo Galilei"],"question":"Who developed the theory of evolution by natural selection?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Copenhagen","incorrectAnswers":["Canberra","Frankfurt","Stockholm"],"question":"What is the capital city of Denmark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Austrian","incorrectAnswers":["Swiss","German","French"],"question":"What nationality did Adolf Hitler have until 1925?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"White Wine","incorrectAnswers":["Sangria","Beer","Port"],"question":"What type of alcoholic drink is traditionally used in the Spanish dish 'Paella'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Beefeaters","incorrectAnswers":["The SAS","The Swiss Guard","The Green Berets"],"question":"What nickname is given to England's Yeoman Warders of the Tower of London?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Incisors","incorrectAnswers":["Molars","Premolars","Slicers"],"question":"The teeth used for biting or cutting are known as _______.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tampa Bay Buccaneers","incorrectAnswers":["Tamba Bay Bears","Tampa Bay Nuggets","Tampa Bay Broncos"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Tampa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Gold","Red"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Pakistan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dan Brown","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Donna Leon","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Lost Symbol'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ten","incorrectAnswers":["Three","Blue","Six"],"question":"What does the word 'diez' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Henry Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Stalin","St. Augustine","Christopher Columbus"],"question":"Which influential historical person was an industrialist who revolutionised mass-production techniques?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gymnasium","incorrectAnswers":["Sauna","Auditorium","Cafeteria"],"question":"In what type of building did Plato and Aristotle teach?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Colt","incorrectAnswers":["A Maggot","A Bunny","An Owlet"],"question":"What is a baby donkey known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Swift ","incorrectAnswers":["Lark","Blackbird","Heron"],"question":"From Which Birds Nest Is Birds Nest Soup Made?","difficulty":"hard"},